everyone welcome back to this Tosca
automation playlist and today we are
going to solve an interesting automation
challenge which I am going to give you
and also I'm going to show you the
solution on how you can solve this
particular problem using the string
operations which are available in Tosca
so we are going to look at two string
operations one is the trim function and
the other is the string replace right so
using this two string operations so
using these two string operations we are
going to solve an automation problem
which you might face while automating
any web application
so let's look at the challenge first
so I'm on this demo webshop site right
where we can add different products into
the cart and we can do a checkout right
so let me show you the scenario which we
are going to look at right so I'm going
to add any product into the cart let's
say this notebook so I click on add to
cart
and then I go to shopping cart
I do I perform the checkout here
and then I go through all of these
checkout screens
okay so performing all of these steps is
not difficult you can scan all these
elements and then you can go ahead uh
doing performing all these steps on the
demo website okay but what I want you to
do is I want you to find out or I want
you to store this order number in a
buffer value so that it can be used for
verification purpose okay so every time
I place an order I want to store this
order number and the challenge is to
extract this order number and store it
in a buffer so that it can be used for
verification okay
so this is the challenge if you want to
resolve this problem on your own then
pause the video and go ahead and work
out this Solution on Tosca and then come
back to the video and watch out what is
the solution which I proposed okay so
now we understood what is the problem
but let's see what is the solution for
this okay so there are basically two
steps first we need to uh
first we need to extract this particular
value or this order number from here and
then we need to store it as a buffer
okay
so for this I have already prepared a
module okay so basically I've scanned
the elements which are present on this
page and this is the module which I have
created okay so you can see here that I
have got one for Success message for
order number okay and if you look at the
properties uh one important thing which
I have done here is I am not capturing
the complete text because the order
number is dynamic right so this order
number will be changing whenever we
place a new order and that's why I have
used regular expression here okay in the
visible in a text so order number and
followed by asterisk which will be uh
which will work for any order number
okay so whatever text is after the order
number that doesn't matter because of
this regular expression on my inner text
so it will be able to identify this
particular element uh be it for any
order number okay so that's the only
important thing while you are scanning
your module you should take care of okay
rest of the things this is a link this
is a button okay so this will be scanned
easily by Tosca and able to identify
uniquely as well you just need to take
care of this order number text which is
a tag Li element okay
so once you do that I have created
already a test case here okay find order
number and what I'm going to do here is
I'm going to drag this module here okay
and first I'm going to buffer the order
number okay
now although I cannot extract the order
number directly here I will show you why
okay so here we need to buffer the order
number so this is the element which gets
the order number for us okay
but the problem is it contains the text
as order number and then which is the
text and then the number okay so you
will not get the number directly
um you cannot buffer the number directly
because everything is in one single
element okay so we have to somehow break
this and get only the number from this
particular text okay
so first let's get the whole text and
then we will see how we can break it
down and just get the number okay
so here uh what I'm going to do is I'm
going to change the action mode to
buffer because I want to buffer this
okay
and then um what I'm going to do is I'm
going to say
uh buffer the inner text okay
and to the value
so that will be B underscore order
okay so it will buffer the value of this
particular element into the buffer B
underscore order right so that will
buffer the value
and let's go ahead and check this first
okay let's see what it is buffering
okay you can see uh the step was
successful and the buffer with name B
underscore order has been set to value
now you can see here there are two
problems one uh it has got the whole
text which is order number and then
cologne and then the order number right
the actual number which we want for our
purpose or which we want
um to store as a buffer for our
verification purpose right the other
problem is you can see there is lot of
white space before and after uh this
text okay so we also need to get rid of
this white space okay and we also need
to extract this number from this
particular buffer okay so these are the
two problems which can be resolved using
the string operations okay so like in
any other language like java.net you do
have string Methods or functions right
similarly Tosca has its own string
operations there are number of
operations uh but I'm going to talk
about two basically uh and these two are
one is the trim function or stream
operation okay which basically removes
the white spaces from the start or end
of the string right just what we need so
we want to trim the white space which is
just before the text and after the text
right and then uh there is string
replace operation so this will basically
replace all occurrences of any
particular input which we are providing
or pattern right with a new value okay
so what is my idea is I want to replace
this order number text okay with a white
space
okay so that's what I want to do
so I will replace this with a white
space and then I will trim all the white
spaces so that I just get the number
here okay which is one four three one
nine one eight and then I'm going to
store it in a buffer which then can be
used anywhere in my test okay
so that's the solution for this problem
and that's what we want to implement
right
so now let me show you how this can be
done okay so for this I am going to use
the key box set buffer
okay and here uh we are going to give a
buffer uh called B underscore order
number
okay
so this is our new uh buffer which will
store the actual order number okay and
we are going to extract it uh in our
value right
so how are we going to do this we have
to use two string operations as I said
right
so here let me first enter the
expression which we'll be using and then
let me explain you how I have formed
this expression right now I'm not typing
this expression because I am not good at
maintaining all this uh curly braces and
brackets if you make a mistake then this
expression will be invalid right so you
have to take special care um while
forming this expression I'm going to
paste this expression in the description
so you can take it from there if you
want okay so let me explain you how I
have formed this expression so first I
am using the trim operation okay
and inside that I am then using the
string replace operation okay so these
are the two operation you can see here
and inside the string replace operation
then we need to pass the actual string
right where we want to replace so that
is B underscore order our buffer which
contains the string right uh so that's
that's the buffer it will get the value
here and then we want to replace this
particular text right which is the order
number followed by colon okay so we want
to replace the string with a white space
and that's why I given two brackets two
square brackets okay and then I am using
the ignore case uh parameter okay so
this ignore case is basically to ignore
uh any upper case or lowercase okay so
no matter if I have typed it in lower
case and in the application it is
uppercase right this will take care of
that okay so it's good to have but it's
not compulsory the most important uh
parts are these two parts where you have
to provide the actual text okay followed
by what you want to replace by what you
want to replace okay
so uh if your expression is correct you
will see uh it is highlighted in this
way in Tosca okay if it is not if it
just displays as normal text then
something is wrong with your expression
okay
so now
um if I go ahead and run this we are
going to get the order number as the
actual number okay and it will be stored
inside the buffer B underscore order
number so let's go ahead and see this by
running this
okay and you can see the step was run
successfully in the log info uh I will
see buffer with name B underscore order
number and it has been set to Value
1431918 okay and this is the order
number which was generated by the
application and now this I have in a
variable right so this is stored in a
buffer variable which I can call anytime
uh in any of my test case just to either
verify the order number or do anything
any modifications on the order number
right so it can be used for many
different purposes so this is a very
common scenario if you are working on
e-commerce web application right
so if you are placing an order on the
website you would want to know what was
the order number because it will be
dynamically generated by the application
and you need to capture it and store it
somewhere if you want to uh go further
in your automation because uh that
verification of that order number is
very important
so this was an automation challenge
which I thought would be useful for you
I hope uh you enjoyed it and you learned
something new today if you were able to
do this in some other way then do let me
know in the comments so that's all for
this video do tune into our channel to
watch more interesting videos on tracing
testoster and many other automation
tools
do subscribe to our Channel if you have
not already so that you get notified
about every update we make uh on our
Channel
so until we meet again
see you and keep learning by watching
different videos on our Channel